Finding Aid for Wealthy Park Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.) records, 1892-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wealthy Park Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.) records
1892-1982
Wealthy Park Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.)
9636 Ba 2
Church originally established as a Sunday school mission of Fountain Street Baptist Church in 1875. The Church was officially incorporated as Wealthy Street Baptist Church in 1886. In 1988, following the move of the church to the Grand Rapids suburbs, the name was changed to Wealthy Park Baptist Church. The record group has been arranged into the following series: Church Administration (2 linear ft.; 1892-1975); David Otis Fuller correspondence and sermon files (9.5 linear ft.; 1928-1985); Missionary correspondence (4.5 linear ft.; 1923-1980); and Photographs (0.1 linear ft.; ca. 1920s-1980s).
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
16 linear feet
The record group is on deposit from the Wealthy Park Baptist Church (donor no. 7614 ). The records came to the library in July 1995.
The record group is open to research.
Wealthy Street Baptist Church in Grand Rapids, Michigan began as a Sunday school mission of the Fountain Street Baptist Church in 1875, and officially organized as a separate church in 1886. From a founding group of 19 members, within 20 years the church grew to a membership of 350 through active evangelism in the surrounding southeast Grand Rapids neighborhood. The church was, and continues to be, a bastion of Baptist fundamentalism.
In 1909 Rev. Oliver W. Van Osdel was installed as Wealthy Street's eighth pastor. Under his direction a major building campaign took place; the church was designed to be a neighborhood gathering place, and had the appearance of a school or community center rather than a traditional church. The new building opened in 1917, the same year that Van Osdel led Wealthy Street and 13 other churches away from the "modernist" local Baptist Association to form the fundamentalist Grand River Valley Baptist Association. Wealthy Street took on a key role nationally among fundamentalists as well, first with the Baptist Bible Union [BBU], and later with the General Association of Regular Baptist Churches [GARBC].
Saving souls and promoting the Bible as the unerring Word of God have always been at the heart of Wealthy Street's mission. At its high point in 1954, the church had 1,717 members and supported 38 missionaries around the world. In addition to Sunday schools, church groups and a neighborhood visitor program, Wealthy Street also started the Children's Bible Hour radio program in 1942; the Michigan Christian Home for the elderly in 1959; and its evening Bible institute, which began in 1941, grew into the Grand Rapids Baptist College and Seminary.
Rev. Van Osdel retired from the pulpit in 1934, and was succeeded by Rev. David Otis Fuller, who was Wealthy Street's pastor for the next 40 years. Fuller was a man of strong fundamentalist convictions, widely known for his uncompromising beliefs and fiery sermons.
By the early 1970s, church membership was declining, due partly to an aging congregation, and also to changes in the surrounding neighborhood, as many Wealthy Street parishioners moved out to the suburbs. The decision to move out of the city was controversial, but in 1988 the church moved into a new $2.5 million complex in suburban Grand Rapids, and changed its name to Wealthy Park Baptist Church. By the early 1990s the church was supporting 50 missionaries, and had 825 members.
Wealthy Park Baptist Church Records have been divided into four series: CHURCH ADMINISTRATION; DAVID OTIS FULLER FILES; MISSIONARY CORRESPONDENCE; and PHOTOGRAPHS. The records document a wide variety of church activities, Reverend David Otis Fuller's career, and the experiences of missionaries who were sponsored by the church.
Subjects:
Wealthy Park Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Association of Baptists for World Evangelism.; Baptists--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Grand Rapids (Mich.)--Church history.; Fuller, David Otis.; Evangelicalism--Michigan.; Fundamentalism--History.; Missions, American--Belgium.; Missions, American--Chile.; Missions, American--China.; Missions, American--Central African Republic.; Missions, American--Brazil.; Missions, American--India.; Missions, American--Japan.; Missions, American--Nigeria.; Missions, American--Philippines.; Missions, American--Congo (Democratic Republic)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Wealthy Park Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Baptist churches--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Grand Rapids (Mich.)--Churches.; Fuller, David Otis.; Missions--China.; Missions--Africa.; Missions--India.
Contributors:
Fuller, David Otis.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sermons.
- Church Administration
  The Church Administration series (2 linear ft.; 1892-1975) contains reports, financial records, correspondence and pamphlets. There is a complete run of Annual Reports for the years 1892 to 1953, although most of the series dates from the 1930s through the mid-1950s. There are also activity reports for several church groups, and the "Building Addition" folder [box 2] contains plans of the downtown church building. Publicity for the church, including tracts by Rev. Fuller, circulars and membership forms are located in the "Pamphlets" folder [box 2].
  - Annual Reports, 1892-1939 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1939-1953; 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Bible School
    - Secretary's Reports, 1928-1947 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1937-1947 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's and Secretary's Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Building Addition, 1954-1959; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Church
    - Business Correspondence, 1928-1944 (Box 2)
    - Clerk's Reports, 1937-1953; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Covenant, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Statistics, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Annual Reports, 1939-1951 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Quarterly Reports, 1943-1953 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1947-1968 (scattered after 1961); 3 folders (Box 2)
  - High School Baptist Young People's Union [B.Y.P.U.] Secretary's and Treasurer's Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Junior B.Y.P.U. Reports, 1948-1951 (Box 2)
  - Junior High B.Y.P.U. Secretary's and Treasurer's Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Missionary Department Records, 1940-1942 (Box 2)
  - Missionary Minute Men Reports, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - Monday Night Bible Class Reports, 1949-1952 (Box 2)
  - Music Department Reports, 1947-1952 (Box 2)
  - Names Dropped from Church Rolls, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 2)
  - Pioneer Girls and Children's Church Reports, 1948-1953 (Box 2)
  - Relief Expenditures (Church Visitor), 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Reports and Statistics from Church Groups, 1940-1949 (Box 2)
  - Senior B.Y.P.U.
    - Secretary's Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Temple Mission Reports, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
  - Women's Missionary Fellowship Reports, 1937-1953; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Young Married Fellowship Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Youth Director's Reports, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
- David Otis Fuller Files
  The David Otis Fuller Files series (9.5 linear ft.; 1928-1984) follows Dr. Fuller's filing system and is divided into two subseries, Correspondence and Sermons.
  Correspondence has been filed in three sections. There are two alphabetical sections, one dating from 1928 to the late 1960s, the other including the years just before and during Fuller's retirement; a third section is filed according to subject. The subseries documents many facets of Dr. Fuller's work. There are queries from parishioners, theological discussions with other ministers, church business, family news, and letters concerning the administration of several Baptist organizations. For a sense of where Fuller's theological views fit in a broader perspective, his correspondence with theologian Nels F.S. Ferre [box 3] and regarding Rev. Billy Graham [box 6] are of interest.
  The Sermons subseries contains virtually every sermon Fuller preached. The sermons are arranged in three different categories: in order by books of the Bible; by subject; and Doctrinal Sermons. There are also four unprocessed folders of sermons.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence (General)
      - A, 1949-1959 (Box 3)
      - American Council of Christian Laymen, 1950-1957 (Box 3)
      - Appelman, Dr. Hyman J., 1948-1958 (Box 3)
      - B, 1948-1960 (Box 3)
      - Book Reviews, 1957-1973 (Box 3)
      - C, 1952-1960 (Box 3)
      - Christensen, Rev. Harold, 1952-1960 (Box 3)
      - Conrad, Wilfred, 1952-1960 (Box 3)
      - D-E, 1948-1960; 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Evangelical Ministerial Union, 1948-1960; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - F, 1948-1960; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Faber, Agnes, 1950-1959 (Box 3)
      - Ferre, Nels F. S., 1955-1959 (Box 3)
      - Fuller, Muriel, 1960-1968 (Box 3)
      - G, 1943-1960; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Gideons, 1949-1960 (Box 3)
      - Goodspeed, Edgar J., 1932 (Box 3)
      - H-K, 1948-1960; 10 folders (Box 4)
      - Knauss, Elizabeth, 1955-1959 (Box 4)
      - Kuiper, Dr. H .J., 1948-1959 (Box 4)
      - L-M, 1949-1960; 6 folders (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous Personal, 1936-1958 (Box 4)
      - Mother, 1929 (Box 4)
      - N, 1948-1960; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - P-W, 1936-1957; 16 folders (Box 5)
      - World War II Soldiers, 1942-1948; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - X-Z, 1948-1956 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Later)
      - A-B, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Bynum, Rev. E. L., 1967-1974 (Box 6)
      - C, 1974-1984 (Box 6)
      - Capague, Samuel N., 1972-1974 (Box 6)
      - D-E, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Emery, A. C., 1974 (Box 6)
      - F-M, 1970-1977; 9 folders (Box 6)
      - Martin, Alfred, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
      - Mellish, Gordon D., 1970-1973 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Personal, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
      - N-W, 1973-1975; 5 folders (Box 6)
      - Wurmbrand, Richard, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
      - X-Z, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Subject Correspondence
      - Baptist Children's Home, 1948-1959 (Box 6)
      - Barthianism, 1950 (Box 6)
      - Berean Baptist Church, 1959 (Box 6)
      - Children's Bible Hour Accounts, 1973 (Box 6)
      - Clippings and Notes, 1936-1971 (Box 6)
      - Conservative Baptist Association Proposed Constitution, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
      - "Counterfeit? Or Genuine? Mark 16?" edited by Fuller, undated (Box 6)
      - Devine, Rev. Robert James, 1936 (Box 6)
      - Dodson, Rev. Kenneth, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
      - Easter, 1936-1941 (Box 6)
      - General Association of Regular Baptist Churches, 1943-1948 (Box 6)
      - Gillett, Rev. Frank, 1955 (Box 6)
      - Gospel Hymnals, 1937-1955 (Box 6)
      - Graham, Rev. Billy, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
      - Grand Rapids Association of Regular Baptist Churches, 1955-1959 (Box 6)
      - Grand Rapids Evangelistic Crusade, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
      - Hayden, Clarence, 1953-1956 (Box 7)
      - Hebrew Christian Alliance of America, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
      - Hoolsema, Rev. A.J., 1937 (Box 7)
      - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1954 (Box 7)
      - Inter-Varsity Christian Fellowship, 1949-1959 (Box 7)
      - Jones, Stanley, 1950-1959 (Box 7)
      - Knauss, Elizabeth, 1955 (Box 7)
      - MacDonald, Donald, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
      - MacDonald, Rev. Walter, 1935-1948 (Box 7)
      - Michelson, Dr. A. V., 1940-1947 (Box 7)
      - Norris, J. Frank, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
      - Nutt, Edward, 1950 (Box 7)
      - "The Occasion for the Revised Version" essay by Fuller, undated (Box 7)
      - Ockenga, Harold, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
      - O'Hairism, 1937-1953 (Box 7)
      - Olin, Claire, 1950 (Box 7)
      - Ordinations, 1938-1959 (Box 7)
      - Philanthropy [Charles Decker], 1947-1958 (Box 7)
      - Presley, Elvis, 1957 (Box 7)
      - Prison Evangelism, Inc., 1955-1958 (Box 7)
      - Regular Baptist Report, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
      - "Requested Re-evaluation: Wealthy Street Baptist Church Retrospectively Re-examined" by Sam Wanner, 1974 (Box 7)
      - Rhee, Syngman [South Korea], 1953-1954 (Box 7)
      - Senators and Representatives, 1951-1957 (Box 7)
      - Singer, Charles, 1952 (Box 7)
      - Springer, Harvey, 1948 (Box 7)
      - Spurgeon's College, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
      - Television Questionnaire, 1952 (Box 7)
      - Ten Commandments Week, 1956 (Box 7)
      - Tornado Fund, 1956 (Box 7)
      - Wagemaker, Herbert, 1953-1957 (Box 7)
      - Wells, Dr. Robert, 1954 (Box 7)
      - "Which Bible? Society Inc.", 1974-1985 (Box 7)
      - Wilson, Florene, 1953-1956 (Box 7)
      - Wilson, T. W., 1949-1953 (Box 7)
  - Sermons
    - Sermons (arranged by books of the Bible)
      - Genesis-Psalms, 1938-1970; 19 folders (Box 7)
      - Proverbs-Revelations, 1929-1971; 35 folders (Box 8)
    - Sermons (arranged by subject)
      - Abraham, 1946; 1960 (Box 8)
      - Balaam, 1947 (Box 8)
      - Bart, Karl, 1963 (Box 8)
      - Belshazzar, 1953 (Box 8)
      - The Bible, 1928-1973 (Box 8)
      - The Bible: Word of God, 1945-1966 (Box 8)
      - Christ: Deity and Virgin Birth, 1941-1949 (Box 8)
      - Daniel, 1965 (Box 8)
      - David, 1945-1954 (Box 8)
      - Elijah, 1932-1964 (Box 8)
      - Eichman, Adolph, 1961 (Box 8)
      - Enoch, 1944-1949 (Box 8)
      - Ezekiel, 1940; 1954 (Box 8)
      - Hezekiah, 1953; 1963 (Box 8)
      - Jehosaphat, 1948 (Box 8)
      - Jeremiah, 1945 (Box 8)
      - Job, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
      - John the Baptist, 1947 (Box 8)
      - Jones, E. Stanley, 1950 (Box 8)
      - Joseph, 1950 (Box 8)
      - Judas, 1955 (Box 9)
      - Lot and His Wife, 1940-1967 (Box 9)
      - Manasseh, 1959 (Box 9)
      - Mary, 1956-1966 (Box 9)
      - Moses and the Israelites, 1940-1965 (Box 9)
      - Noah, 1949 (Box 9)
      - Paul, 1932-1971; 3 folders (Box 9)
      - Peter, 1946-1969 (Box 9)
      - Pilate, 1941-1962 (Box 9)
      - Samson, 1965-1970 (Box 9)
      - Stephen, 1943-1947 (Box 9)
    - Doctrinal Sermons
      - Assurance, 1956-1964 (Box 9)
      - Backsliders, 1943-1964 (Box 9)
      - Baptism, 1931-1969 (Box 9)
      - Believers (Life of), 1929-1956; 6 folders (Box 9)
      - Bible School, 1951-1962 (Box 9)
      - "Can the Dead Communicate with the Living?" (series), 1930-1946 (Box 9)
      - Catholicism (Lent), 1948-1970 (Box 9)
      - Children, 1955-1962 (Box 9)
      - Christ
        - Atonement-Cross-Blood, 1928-1964; 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Birth and Early Childhood, 1949-1965 (Box 9)
        - Deity and Virgin Birth, 1929-1956; 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Jesus-Saviour, 1937-1965; 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Names and Titles (series), 1939-1965 (Box 9)
        - Parables of Christ, 1938-1952; 2 folders (Box 9)
        - "Pontius Pilate Questions Christ", 1951 (Box 9)
        - Pre-existence, 1929-1934 (Box 9)
        - Sufferings, Crucifixion, Death, 1930-1961 (Box 9)
      - Covetousness, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
      - Creation, 1966 (Box 10)
      - Crises, 1959 (Box 10)
      - Cross, 1946-1954 (Box 10)
      - Death, 1934-1966 (Box 10)
      - Deliverance, 1960 (Box 10)
      - Devil, Destiny of, 1930-1960 (Box 10)
      - Devil, Power of, 1927-1970 (Box 10)
      - Divorce and Remarriage, 1939-1959 (Box 10)
      - Ecumenical Movement, 1965 (Box 10)
      - Education, 1932-1949 (Box 10)
      - Election, 1950-1963 (Box 10)
      - Eternal Life, 1948 (Box 10)
      - "Evil and Theodicy", 1962-1966 (Box 10)
      - Evolution, 1936-1939 (Box 10)
      - Failure, 1952 (Box 10)
      - Faith, 1928-1956; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Faith (Knowledge-Results), 1941-1965 (Box 10)
      - Fallen Angels, 1957 (Box 10)
      - Fire, 1939-1956 (Box 10)
      - Flying Saucers, 1954 (Box 10)
      - Freedom (God's), 1936-1948 (Box 10)
      - Fundamentalism, 1938-1960 (Box 10)
      - God, Attributes of, 1928-1967 (Box 10)
      - Grace, 1934-1972 (Box 10)
      - High Priest, 1966 (Box 10)
      - History, 1948 (Box 10)
      - Holy Spirit, 1928-1970 (Box 10)
      - Honor and Holiness, 1951-1956 (Box 10)
      - "Huis Bezoek"-Christian Hollanders, 1959-1964 (Box 10)
      - Humbleness-Humility, 1952 (Box 10)
      - Hypocrisy, 1954 (Box 10)
      - Idolatry, 1946-1957 (Box 11)
      - Incarnation, 1965 (Box 11)
      - Inspiration, 1935 (Box 11)
      - Israel, Children of, 1945-1960 (Box 11)
      - "Isms", 1931-1953 (Box 11)
      - Jews, 1943-1966 (Box 11)
      - Judgment, 1928-1967; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Judgment Seat of Christ, 1953 (Box 11)
      - Justice of God, 1946 (Box 11)
      - Justification, 1947-1956 (Box 11)
      - Labor Unions and Lodges, 1937 (Box 11)
      - Law of God,1945-1962, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Lepers, 1954-1967 (Box 11)
      - Liquor, 1957 (Box 11)
      - Love, 1930-1972 (Box 11)
      - Love-Courtship-Marriage, 1965 (Box 11)
      - Man, 1935 (Box 11)
      - Membership, 1930-1956 (Box 11)
      - Mercy, 1943; 1962 (Box 11)
      - Messiah, 1955 (Box 11)
      - Missions-Missionaries, 1931-1955 (Box 11)
      - Modernism, 1930-1943 (Box 11)
      - Names, 1953 (Box 11)
      - Navy Chaplaincy, 1945 (Box 11)
      - "Numerical Miracles of Scripture", 1955 (Box 11)
      - Obedience, 1947 (Box 11)
      - "Once-Study in Four Onces", 1967 (Box 11)
      - Ordinances, 1950-1964 (Box 11)
      - Patience, 1947-1954 (Box 11)
      - "Pious Softness", 1952 (Box 11)
      - Prayer, 1928-1969 (Box 11)
      - Protestantism, 1951 (Box 11)
      - Repentance, 1947-1955 (Box 11)
      - Resurrection, 1934-1953 (Box 11)
      - Reward of Righteous, 1934-1962 (Box 11)
      - Satan, Fallen Angels and Anti-Christ, 1931-1961 (Box 11)
      - Slaves-Slavery, 1965 (Box 11)
      - Socialism, 1937-1966 (Box 11)
      - Soul Winning, 1929-1966 (Box 11)
      - Space, 1961 (Box 11)
      - Spirit-Filled Life, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
      - Suicide, 1946-1948 (Box 11)
      - Sympathy, 1948 (Box 11)
      - Tabernacle, 1946-1954 (Box 11)
      - Temptation-Testing, 1947-1953 (Box 11)
      - Tithing, 1930-1967 (Box 11)
      - Wicked, Destiny of the, 1931-1969 (Box 11)
      - Unprocessed sermons, 4 folders (Box 12)
- Missionary Correspondence
  Missionary Correspondence (4.5 linear ft.; 1923-1980) contains letters and circulars from Wealthy Park missionaries who served all over the world. The correspondence provides a strong sense of the missionaries' religious convictions, as they often endured hardship and deprivation in isolated areas. Many of the letters also contain detailed descriptions of indigenous cultures, living conditions, and war-time experiences.
  The series is filed in alphabetical order, by name of missionary or sponsoring organization. While there is no comprehensive list of missionaries by country of service, the booklet "What God Hath Wrought!" [box 16] provides an overview, with biographical sketches of long-term Wealthy Park missionaries; pamphlets in the "Missionary Conference" folders [box 14] also list missionaries by country of service.
  - Association of Baptists for World Evangelism [ABWE]
    - 1935-1942, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Leaflets and Newsletters, 1939-1942 (Box 12)
    - 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - 1973-1977 (Box 12)
  - Baptist Mid-Missions, 1967-1969 (Box 12)
  - Barnett, Victor and Margaret, 1931-1977; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Bayley, Keith, 1961-1973 (Box 13)
  - Belgian Gospel Mission, Inc., 1964 (Box 13)
  - Berends, George and Joy, 1962-1973 (Box 13)
  - Beukema, Robert and Winona, 1948-1973; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Brodeur, Roxanne, 1972-1975 (Box 13)
  - Commons, Harold, 1958-1963 (Box 13)
  - Commons, William and Sharon, 1967-1976 (Box 13)
  - Danielson, Carl, 1949-1953 (Box 13)
  - Dannenberg, Shirley and Earl, 1968-1974 (Box 13)
  - DeCook, Joseph and Joyce, 1969-1974 (Box 13)
  - DeLange, Lena, 1935-1942 (Box 13)
  - DeVries, Henry and Gladys, 1938-1957; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - DeVries, Henry Jr. and Virginia, 1954-1972 (Box 13)
  - DeVries, John and Florence, 1947-1974 (Box 13)
  - DeWaard, Arlene, 1952-1963 (Box 13)
  - Dyksterhouse, Jay and Norma, 1953-1970 (Box 13)
  - Ebersole, Gene and Russell, 1953-1974 (Box 13)
  - Emmett, Adrianna (Raidt) and Edward, 1949-1974 (Box 13)
  - Erdman, Margaret, 1961-1970 (Box 13)
  - Evangelical Alliance Mission (T. Pietsch), 1948-1958; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Friederichsen, Paul D., 1939-1941 (Box 13)
  - Griswold, William and Jean, 1965-1974 (Box 13)
  - Helser, Albert, 1937-1939 (Box 13)
  - Hiawatha Land Independent Baptist Mission, 1961-1974 (Box 14)
  - Hoyt, Esther and Sommers, Lulu, 1936-1977; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Jewish Missions, 1946; 1958-1960 (Box 14)
  - Kleinschmidt, Fred, 1970-1973 (Box 14)
  - Kohler, Robert and Grace, 1940-1941 (Box 14)
  - Larson, Charles and Ella Mae, 1936-1939 (Box 14)
  - McCabe, Joseph, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Merrado, Leonardo and Hazel, 1936-1941 (Box 14)
  - Message to Israel, 1965-1969 (Box 14)
  - Missionary Conferences, 1967-1975; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Nelson, Julia (Cole) and William, 1939-1980; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Parks (Teachout], Betty, 1956-1969 (Box 14)
  - Peck, Effie, 1931-1967; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Pent, Philip, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Peterson, Floyd and Lenore, 1935-1964; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Post, Mabel, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Pullen, Gordon and Naomi, 1949-1966 (Box 14)
  - Ramabai Mukti Mission, 1959-1977 (Box 14)
  - Ramiah, Arthur and Elizabeth, 1932-1942 (Box 14)
  - Rath, Wilma, 1963-1974 (Box 14)
  - Rathbun, Edward and Marion, 1965-1974 (Box 14)
  - Retan, Lewis and Lucille, 1952-1982; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Reynhout, Hubert and Doris, 1937-1942 (Box 15)
  - Rowland, Robert and Pat, 1958-1970 (Box 15)
  - Sarjeant, Jack and Pearl, 1950-1969 (Box 15)
  - Scheltema, Chester and Marjorie, 1960-1965 (Box 15)
  - Scheltema, Herwin and Ruth, 1958-1974; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Shattuck, Betty, 1949-1974; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Sloan, James and Joyce, 1972-1975 (Box 15)
  - Snodgrass, William and Lorna, 1960-1974 (Box 15)
  - Southern Spanish Mission, 1955-1959 (Box 15)
  - Steed, Bernice, 1923-1958; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Sterkenberg, Richard and Betty, 1956-1974; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Stoner, William and Rosalind, 1958-1974; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Stull, Willard and Grace, 1968-1974 (Box 15)
  - Sudan Interior Mission, 1965-1968 (Box 15)
  - Swingle, Aita and Robert, 1960-1977 (Box 15)
  - Teachout, Betty and Donald, 1965-1974 (Box 15)
  - TerMeer, Albert and Eva, 1937-1976; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - TerMeer, Donald and Jean, 1962-1982 (Box 16)
  - Trans-World Missionary Services, 1956-1961 (Box 16)
  - Turner, Eugenia and Glen, 1949-1974 (Box 16)
  - Ubbink, Elmer and Mary Jane, 1969-1974 (Box 16)
  - Valk, Barbara, 1953-1983 (Box 16)
  - VanDyke, Gary and Gail, 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - Various, 1933-1974; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Ver Burg, Mary Ellen, 1949-1961 (Box 16)
  - Verlee, James and Mary, 1959-1970 (Box 16)
  - Verlee, Richard and Ruth, 1951-1965 (Box 16)
  - Washington, Starlon, 1975-1977 (Box 16)
  - "What God Hath Wrought!" (booklet], 1964 (Box 16)
  - White, Dorothy, 1952-1963 (Box 16)
  - Wimer, Arthur and Pat, 1968-1973 (Box 16)
- Photographs
  Photographs (1 folder and 1 album; c.1920s-1980s) contains pictures of the Fuller family and their missionary friends; the album contains photographs taken by missionaries during the 1920s and 1930s in China, India, Eastern Europe, Africa and South America.
  - Fuller family and Missionaries, circa 1920s-1980s (Box 16)
  - Missionary Photograph Album, circa 1922-1932 (Box 16)